Guide to the Janet G. Travell papers, 1910-1997 MS0704.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Personal papers, books, and certificates, 1926-1996; MS0704 Series 7; 6.5 Linear feet (Box 97, Box 98, Box 99, Box 100, Box 101, Box 102, Box 103, Box 104, Box 105)
  - Books: Mysofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, 1983 (Box 103, Folder 11)
    by Janet Travell and David Simons (Upper half of body; Volume 1)
  - Books: Office Hours: Day and Night, 1968 (Box 103, Folder 12)
    by Janet Travell
  - Books: Mysofascial Pain and Dysfunction: The Trigger Point Manual, 1999 (Box 103, Folder 13)
    by Janet Travell and David Simons (Upper half of body; Volume 1, 2nd edition) [presented to GW University Archives by Lippincott, Williams & Wilkins, Publishers 2001]
  - Books: Book catalog and brochures from Lippincott Williams & Wilkins, 1998 ca. (Box 103, Folder 14)
    featuring Dr. Travell's work, addition to collection via donor gift from Virginia Street, June 2001
  - Books: National Association of Myofascial Trigger Point Therapists (NAMTPT) newsletter, 2000 (Box 103, Folder 15)
    Along with membership list, addition to collection via donor gift from Virginia Street, June 2001
  - Framed photos: Dr. Janet Travell - taken in White House office for cover of Modern Medicine magazine, 05/19/1961 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    Oversize Material
  - Framed photos: Dr. Travell at U.S. Naval Hospital, 1961 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Framed photos: Department of Pharmacology, Cornell University Medical College, 12/1949 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Framed photos: Dr. Janet Travell, 1940 ca. (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Plaques: Physician's Prayer, undated (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Plaques: Plaque with inscription of gratitude to Dr. Travell from Dr. Thomas Webber, 1969 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Plaques: Plaque given to Dr. Travell on the occasion of her appointment as Personal Physician to President Kennedy, 1961 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Oversize Drawings: Miscellaneous drawings and charts, undated (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Oversize Drawings: Mr. Clarke's drawings for Federation Intermittent Claudication Paper Drawings - Hysteria paper, 1945 ca. (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Oversize Drawings: Mechanical Drawings for seating design, 1952 (Box 104, Folder 10)
    Removed from Box 35: folder 2
  - Oversize Certificate: American Academy of Orofacial Pain, making Dr. Travell an honorary member, 1993 (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Artifacts: Book bag, undated (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Artifacts: Lab coat, undated (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Artifacts: Two jump ropes, undated (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Artifacts: Eight rubber stamps of body for use by Dr. Travell in charting pain points, undated (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Artifacts: One 40 gram tube for applying ethyl chloride spray, made by the Gebauer Chemical Company, undated (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Artifacts: Envelope containing a calling card from Dr. Travell's mother to her father, Book of Common Prayer from Dr. Travell's parent's wedding; a hand fan, 1899 ca. (Box 105, Folder 6)